Khaleel AL-Haboub

Software Engineering Innovation Creative Design Entrepreneurship

Passionate engineer with an entrepreneurial spirit who utilizes creativity, leadership, and teamwork to execute solutions that create customer value.

PROFILE

NAME:

Khaleel Abdulrahman Al-Haboub

MOBILE:

(966) 59 422 3341

EMAIL:

Kh.haboub@gmail.com

ADDRESS:

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

NATIONALITY, STATUS:

Saudi Citizen, Single

WEBSITE:

http://khaleel.me

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/khaleelalhaboub

COURSES

- Business Planning
- PMP Exam Prep.
- AdWords Fundamentals
- Mobile Sites Design
- Google Analytics (GAIQ)
- Scaling up Startups

SKILLS

Through my professional experience, I have acquired various skills and disciplines in **business**, **tech**, and **design**. This results in communicating design thinking process and building human-centered products.

BUSINESS SKILLS

Directed and participated in developing **projects plans** and their **strategies** from a **business and technical perspective**. Engaged in developing **new business ideas** including **business planning**, **technical evaluation**, and **estimation**.

Also, have worked in building and launching **digital marketing campaigns**, identifying the project's **minimum viable product (MVP)** that meets end-user needs, and **measure** /analyzing users' **behavior** and their **interaction** with the product.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Directed and participated in building tech-based projects. Starting with a project discovery, analyzing complex technical requirements, connecting design thinking to agile sprints with user story mapping, designing high-level software architecture, resulting in delivering a world-class product that meets the client expectation.

Also, defined the company's **development process**, structured the **development team** hierarchy including **reporting**, **reviewing**, **communication channels**, **development style guide**, and more.

DESIGN SKILLS

Dealt with various clients and stakeholders shaping products experiences. Starting with understanding the **user's persona**, **mapping user's journey**, crafting user's **storyboarding**, **sketching product's wireframes**, and **prototyping** to validate the outcomes with the end-users. This process is being done using various methods including **Design Sprint** framework.

Also, directed and participated in the product design process to produce a design that aligns with an overarching strategy. This process starts with identifying the goals resulting in a comprehensive design system that provides consistent, reusable UI (user interface) components using various tools including Sketch, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator.





Entrepreneurs Shaping Saudi Arabia's Future

Honored to receive Forbes Middle East's Entrepreneurs Shaping Saudi Arabia's Future award for building an innovation-driven business in two consecutive years 2015 & 2016.

EDUCATION

B.S., Software Engineering

Graduation: 2009 - 2017 Distinctive Student in 2011, 2013, 2014

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Accredited university by ABET

RANKED WORLD TOP 189TH BY QS TIMES

TECHNOLOGY & LANG

WEB

- Javascript: Vanilla, NodeJS, AngularJS [1, 2+]
- CSS / Less & Sass
- NPM Gulp Bower
- PHP (Vanilla, Frameworks)
- .Net EF/Core
- · Rest API's GraphQL

MOBILE

- · Android (RxJava, RxAndroid)
- Cross-Platform Apps (ionic)

GENERAL

- Java EE
- C/C++, C#
- · Oracle Business Process Mgt.
- Cloud Services: Azure, docker
- CMS: WordPress, Drupal
- E-Commerce / M-Commerce: Open Cart, Magento

EXPERIENCE

Indielabs, LLC. / CTO & Director of innovation lab

June 2014 - Current

Responsible for overall product design, product development, and customer delivery. Lead all aspects of software project management, including all projects estimation, make vs. buy analysis, solving a complex problem, for a portfolio of 40+ projects.

- Designed and led multiple cross-functional workshops translating stakeholders vision, consumer insights, trends and competitive landscape into product ideas.
- Developed and managed product innovation activities including product pipelines
- Managed & coordinated remote development teams and the in-house team.
- Accumulate market know-how, to enhance and manage knowledge on projects.
- Set standards and project processes for delivery teams, mentor team members and make staffing decisions for the development team.
- · Passion for learning, exploring and encourage the development team to utilize new web platforms, emerging standards, tools and best practices
- Developed numerous innovative cloud-based mobile solutions.
- Expertise in creating and deploying native (iOS and Android Apps) and hybrid mobile apps on both Apple and Google's app stores.

Google / GSA

Jun 2013 – Jun 2014

Google Ambassador Program is an opportunity for students to act as liaisons between Google and their universities.

KEY RESPONSIBILITIES:

Worked with local Google teams. Planned and hosted events on campus. Acted as a campus contact for Google teams. Built relationships on campus with faculty and student groups on behalf of Google.

Saudi Aramco / Summer Intern

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

Worked at Saudi Aramco Entrepreneurship Center (Wa'ed) as a Summer Intern. Wa'ed was pursuing a pioneering program to enable KFUPM students to spend their summer training/co-op period building their own actual companies around their own creative business ideas.

KEY ACTIVITIES:

- Developed business plan for new tech-based ventures.
- Exposed to various methods and concepts for tech-based ventures creation including SaaS, MVP, Bootstrapping, Lean Startup, Business Canvas.
- Exposed to numerous new product design tactics including picking the right venture name, color theory and golden ratio and more.
- Built a new SaaS-based online venture.
- Managed the user experience test sessions, and analyzed the outcomes.

HONORABLE MENTIONS

SCALING BUSINESSES

Successfully planned and executed the company scaling initiative by opening a new branch in Egypt. Responsible for locating new branch office, hiring staff, knowledge transfer and more.

WA'ED STARTUP LAB

Fortunate to be in WA'ED's 1st batch of business entrepreneurs. This was an excellent opportunity to learn the business tactics from world-class mentors including MIT Sloan grads & McKinsey.

PMP®

Currently working to become a PMI® Project Management Professional, and obtain the PMP certification. Finished all exam requirements, and waiting for the certification exam.

KFUPM / Web Developer (Part-time)

Jan 2011 - May 2013

Designed and developed responsive web applications using SharePoint, PHP, and Bootstrap for the system engineering department at KFUPM.

- Maintained existing sites based on MS. SharePoint.
- Designed and developed new web services utilizing custom PHP frameworks.
- Helped create and implement new ideas for ways to increase users' engagement.
- Successfully adapted and thrived in a fast-paced work environment with rapidly changing goals.

Freelancing / Web Designer & Developer

2008 - 2012

Worked as a **web designer/ developer** online with various clients. Acquired an essential experience in dealing with **different type of customers**, working **under pressure** and tight **deadlines**, driving projects **forward**, and mainly the **ability** to **work with minimum supervision**.



PORTFOLIO

Sarahah.com Sarahah.com

Sarahah.com helps you in discovering your strengths and areas for improvement by receiving honest feedback from your employees and your friends in a private manner.

- Managed & redesigned the platform software architecture to hold the massive rapid requests.
- · Designed and developed the product's new strategies to increase the user engagement.
- Managed product pipeline and new features' introduction to inline with the available resources and budget.
- Directed all aspects of the product delivery process. Starting with the design, development & publishing of Sarahah's apps on Apple and Google's app stores.
- Occupies the #1 top spot in the Apple Store in 30 countries, with apps download exceeded 50 million.
- Successfully increased user engagement on the platform from only 30M registered users to 60M monthly active users.
- Prude to build a product that has reached people around the globe with page views exceeded 1 billion views.

EJAR

EJAR is an app from the Ministry of Housing, represented by its EJAR initiative, aims to facilitate the search for the registered realestate agencies.

- Project Management
- Mobile Development
- UI/UX Design

LAND.LY/ WASET

B8AK

B8ak allows you to get quality home maintenance services. We will connect you with verified service providers in your area and based on your maintenance request we will get you a quality handyman.

UI/UX Design

LAND.LY/B8AK

FEEEDZ

Feeedz is a centralized platform for the Saudi community to keep them up-to-date on the latest offers in the market. Users will be able to access all available offers across the country.

- Project Management
- UI/UX Design

LAND.LY/FEEEDZ